<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-14T22:59:09-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Atomwell</title><subtitle>Atomwell's unique metal 3d printer creates solid, 100% dense, precise, and strong metal objects. We manufacture and sell our selective powder deposition printer, materials, and accessories.  We also offer a 3d printing service for your parts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welding Printers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/printers/2020/10/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welding Printers" /><published>2020-10-14T21:07:07-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T21:07:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/printers/2020/10/14/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/printers/2020/10/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;“Welding printers” are metal 3d printers that build a part up by melting metal wire or powder onto the part layer by layer.
These types of printers have many benefits over DMLS, but they have some major downsides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parts are not fully dense.&lt;/strong&gt; Welding is an inherently messy process, leaving inconsistent voids in the part.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grinding requirement.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually the additive printing must be paused periodically to grind away excess material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No small features.&lt;/strong&gt; Welding does not scale down well to features that are millimeters in size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atomwell’s proprietary selective powder deposition process prints parts that are 100% dense without post-processing, requires no grinding, and supports very small features.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="printers" /><summary type="html">“Welding printers” are metal 3d printers that build a part up by melting metal wire or powder onto the part layer by layer. These types of printers have many benefits over DMLS, but they have some major downsides: Parts are not fully dense. Welding is an inherently messy process, leaving inconsistent voids in the part. Grinding requirement. Usually the additive printing must be paused periodically to grind away excess material. No small features. Welding does not scale down well to features that are millimeters in size.</summary></entry></feed>